<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Kyle Hayes]]></title>
  <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-11-13T20:01:39-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kyle Hayes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Find a place for everything]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/11/13/find-a-place-for-everything/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-13T17:28:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/11/13/find-a-place-for-everything</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it sounds like a basic principle, but how many of us follow it? If you find that your workspaces or home are constantly getting filled with clutter every few days, it&#8217;s possible you don&#8217;t have a place for everything!</p>

<p>I spent this whole weekend reorganizing my home office to not only ensure that every object had a place, but also items that are used less often are put in harder to reach spots and items that I use or need more frequently in very easy to reach places. That way, when I&#8217;m done with something that I use often, it immediately gets put back in its spot.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve also found that the shoebox containers from The Container Store are very nice to have and I highly recommend buying their 20 count box. Pair those with a label maker and you are set off to a great start towards being more organized.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/11/08/switching-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-08T08:12:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/11/08/switching-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, at least for now, I&#8217;ve decided that I was tired of dealing with Wordpress. In an effort to lower my costs and headache for owning and operating a personal blog, Octopress paired with Jekyll seemed like an awesome alternative for someone who enjoys writing in plain text as much as myself.</p>

<p>I was <a href="http://blog.rebeccamurphey.com/switching-to-octopress">inspired</a> by a couple of <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">folks</a> to make the switch. All in all, it was actually not too bad once I got the latest version of Ruby and RVM <a href="http://brandonbohling.com/2011/08/27/Installing-Jekyll-on-Mac/">setup on my Mac</a>.</p>

<p><em>EDIT</em></p>

<p>It&#8217;s also worthy to note that I used <a href="https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp">exitwp</a> to migrate my wordpress content into markdown. I realize there are a few bugs that I need to iron out and will do that soon.</p>

<p>Furthermore, check out <a href="http://pages.github.com/">http://pages.github.com/</a> if you are ever interested in free static stite hosting on github. Seems pretty good for a personal blog setup.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lee, the Patriot]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/10/14/lee-the-patriot/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-14T01:46:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/10/14/lee-the-patriot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, as I looked upon the new resting place of my dear great Uncle Lee, I
had a revelation that left me distraught. Lee was a part of the World War II
generation—specifically, he fought and was wounded in the Battle of Bulge.
That global conflict, the worst our world has seen, defines to me what the
cost of freedom was for the United States we have today. As a citizen of this
country, I was embarrassed and disappointed with myself when I realized how
much my generation and I take this costly freedom for granted. I don&#8217;t think
we can truly appreciate it since we have not suffered what the world suffered
then.</p>

<p>Lee&#8217;s generation knows the pain and suffering of what it means to be free—they
understand patriotism on a different level from what my generation could ever
imagine. I&#8217;m so thankful for the amazing patriot he was and his bold testament
to the world as such a great, funny, and loving man to his family, first and
foremost to his wife. Naturally, my first regret was that I did not know him
better and did not visit with him more. His wartime generation could teach my
generation a lot if we were so humble to listen.</p>

<p>As I sit here and think about what patriotism means to me and consider what it
must have meant to Lee, I can&#8217;t help but shed tears in the memory of what dies
along with him—an understanding of what it means to be an American, a citizen
of this great country.</p>

<p>Funerals bring one to reflect on one’s own life. Lee’s passing encouraged me
to have a more serious and solemn appreciation for all of the brave men and
women of our nation who serve and have served us so dutifully.</p>

<p>My deepest sympathy and compassion go out to my family in this sorrowful time.
May we not dwell on what we&#8217;ve lost, but instead look forward to what he
taught us and how he inspired us.</p>

<p>Rest in peace, dear Lee.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ReddPics Bookmarklet]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/10/11/reddpics-bookmarklet/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-11T23:33:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/10/11/reddpics-bookmarklet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you didn&#8217;t know already, <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/ggjab/til_that_you_can_replace_redditcom_with/">you can replace reddit.com with reddpics.com on
any subreddit to view it as an image gallery</a>. I was tired of doing the
actual replacing so I created a bookmarklet to do it for me.</p>

<p>Drag the following link to your bookmarks bar: <a href="document.location=document.location.href.replace(%22reddit%22,%22reddpics%22);">ReddPics This</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's about the customer service]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/06/13/its-about-the-customer-service/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-13T15:22:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/06/13/its-about-the-customer-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some companies get it, some don&#8217;t; quality customer service <em>does</em> matter and
<em>does</em> leave a lasting impression. From the time an individual first walks
into a store, logs in online, or approaches the host/hostess at a restaurant,
the subconscious evaluation of customer service begins. Akin to first
impressions when meeting someone for the first time, immediately you begin
making judgements about how you are treated, e.g., whether you were greeted in
a courteous manner, asked if you need help, etc. From this point forward, it&#8217;s
the company&#8217;s duty to draw you in, and give you reason to hand over your hard
earned money in exchange for their product or service. You likely preconceived
doing this anyway otherwise you would not have approached them in the first
place. However, there are many alternatives and you could change your mind and
go somewhere else if you&#8217;ve not found what you&#8217;re looking for or you&#8217;ve not
received the service you expect.</p>

<p>I am constantly on the lookout for companies and organizations who treat their
customers well. In many cases, I&#8217;m likely to pay more for a product or service
to receive such quality treatment. Some of the companies who top my list are
those whom offer great customer service that may not be known for it or may be
less expected to are Zappos.com, Apple, Amazon.com, and Costco. They have no
particular obligation as say Nordstrom does in offering the best service in
their industry. Yet, they understand the value. I&#8217;ve had a couple of
interactions with each of these recently and would like to lay them out
beginning with Apple.</p>

<h2>Apple</h2>

<p>One evening when making spiced apple cider last autumn, I received a phone
call. I went to pick up my iPhone and unlocked it—as I did, the phone some how
slipped out of my hand and plopped, fully submerged into the large bowl of hot
apple cider (slightly ironic). I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever reacted to something so
quickly! I reached into the bowl to save the life of my iPhone, wiped it down
and took a can of compressed air to try and get as much liquid out as
possible. All seemed fine and it appeared to have been saved—until the next
day. Unfortunately whatever damage had been done had set into the electronics
of the phone and I was not able to hear the person on the other line very well
when listening to the earpiece. Naturally, I was quite bummed.</p>

<p>After much consideration, I decided I was going to take it to the Genius Bar
at my local Apple Store to see how much it was going to cost to repair. For
all my mobile Apple products, I always buy AppleCare as I&#8217;ve found it&#8217;s
usually pretty good insurance. Unfortunately, one of the things AppleCare does
not cover is liquid damage. Nonetheless, I committed to myself I was going to
tell the truth and not try to be like some of those people that I&#8217;ve seen go
in and claim that the phone was not dropped in water even though the genius
can clearly see that the liquid sensors in the iPhone have been activated.</p>

<p>When I arrived at the Apple store, I told the genius exactly what had
happened. She was very understanding and asked to look at the iPhone to see if
the liquid sensors had been damaged. After about five minutes, she came back
and said the liquid sensors were not activated and questioned tongue-in-cheek,
&#8220;so, you&#8217;re having trouble with your speaker, huh? Well, geez, that&#8217;s
unfortunate, we need to get a replacement iPhone for you to see if that
resolves the issue.&#8221; I was thrilled as she had just finished telling me it was
going to be something in the range of $250 to get it replaced. <em>This</em> is
customer service.</p>

<h2>Amazon.com</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve long been a customer of Amazon.com and am a strong advocate of their
retail philosophies. There are many things that I love about their shopping
experience, from their breadth of product offerings, to their Prime shipping
service. However, I would like to focus on their Subscribe &amp; Save service. If
you have not had the pleasure of ordering a product with Subscribe &amp; Save, I
highly recommend you find something of interest and give it a try, it really
is worth it.</p>

<p>Offered on a limited set of products that you would likely purchase routinely,
Subscribe &amp; Save allows you to opt-in to receive a designated item or usually
a multi-pack of items every so often. For example, one of the things I have
subscribed to is three packages of cat litter for our automatic litterbox. I
receive these three cartons of litter every three months and it is
automatically shipped. The advantages are for the customer is 1) you can
cancel any time so you are not obligated to a pre-determined number of
shipments, 2) you get free shipping on the item, 3) you get a 15% discount off
the purchase price and 4) you get to choose the delivery frequency. Pretty
sweet deal if you ask me. One might think that this is one of those marketing
ploys where they make the offer look attractive by getting you to sign up and
making it difficult to unsubscribe or they don&#8217;t warn you when a shipment is
about to go out to give you enough time to cancel. I&#8217;m happy to report it is
not at all like this. In fact, Amazon sends you an email a few days before the
shipment leaves the warehouse to give you time to cancel. <em>This</em> is customer
service.</p>

<h2>Costco</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve been a member of Costco for quite some time as they consistently offer
quality products. I find the small membership fee to be well worth the value
and service I get from this retailer. If you are familiar with Costco, you are
probably also familiar with their lifetime unconditional guarantee they offer
on most of their products (&#8220;most?&#8221;, yes, unfortunately customers began abusing
the system on things like computers, televisions, and cell phones, so they had
to limit some items to a three month guarantee). This incredible guarantee
states that if you are ever dissatisfied with any product or purchase you
make, you can return the item(s) for a full refund, no questions asked.</p>

<p>I have known about this little perk for some time now, but never had the
oppotunity to utilize it—until recently. A year and a half ago, I purchased an
HP inkjet printer from Costco. I&#8217;ve been a long time fan of HP, until the past
couple of printers and ink supplies I&#8217;ve purchased. This printer worked pretty
well for the first six months. However, the next six months it got really bad
with paper jams so much so that only about 10% of our print jobs were
successful. I was really bummed, until I realized that this was an opportunity
to take advantage of the Costco guarantee. I called them up and asked if I
could bring the printer in for a refund, they responded that as long as I had
the receipt as well as the cables and such that came with it, it was not an
issue. I did just that. The process was very simple and was a very normal
return process—I didn&#8217;t even have the original box. <em>This</em> is customer
service.</p>

<h2>Zappos.com</h2>

<p>Finally, I would like to describe my most recent act of quality customer
service which was with Zappos.com. As someone who rarely has time to visit a
brick and mortar store to shop, especially for shoes, Zappos.com has become an
excellent convenience. While their prices seem to be standard and aren&#8217;t much
cheaper if I bought them in person some where, their service is incredible and
their model is second-to-none. For starters, they offer free shipping to you
<em>and</em> free shipping back to them if you decide to return your purchase. For
VIP members (which is no extra cost to become one), that shipping is
automatically upgraded to overnight. They take the baton even further by
offering a very user-friendly site that is clear, fast, and offers an
excellent alternative to in person shoe shopping—by providing pictures and
video of all angles of the shoe. Finally, to top it off, I had a specific
scenario that really made this company stand out.</p>

<p>While I&#8217;ve only ever purchased shoes from them, I decided to take a look at
the options they had for other clothes. I found a safe bet in a pair of jeans
that appeared to fit the bill and were at a good price point. I made the
purchase and went about my business. The next day I had the following email in
my inbox:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hello Kyle,</p></blockquote>

<p>We were unable to process your order for the Nautica Relaxed Fit Jean on order
number Order #[removed]. Please accept our sincerest apologies. Regrettably,
the merchandise did not pass our quality inspection and we do not have a
replacement available in stock in the size and color you requested.</p>

<p>Since the item is unavailable, we have canceled your order and voided the
authorization on your credit card. Please be advised that it could take your
bank 2-10 business days to release the authorization placed on your account
for this order.</p>

<p>We have conducted a search of other internet retailers and were unable to find
the item available elsewhere. In case you&#8217;d like to wait and see if we get
this item back in stock, we have added you to our &#8220;notify me&#8221; list. Being
placed on the &#8220;notify me&#8221; list does not require any obligation on your part.
Please review the link below for more information about our Notification List
and how it works:</p>

<p>http://www.zappos.com/general-questions#out-of-stock</p>

<p>This order is not indicative of the high quality of service and products we
strive to provide our customers. As a gesture of goodwill, we have issued a
$10.00 coupon which you may use toward your next purchase at Zappos.com. Below
is the coupon code you will need to receive your discount&#8230;.</p>

<p>I was astounded. How could an online retailer give me such joy after informing
they were not able to complete my order. Let&#8217;s point out a few items of
interest here.</p>

<p>First, I received this email the day after I made the purchase. In cases where
I have had back orders in the past with other retailers, the company has
notified me no less than a week later and they apologize then simply say it
will be in when it will be in.</p>

<p>The next point of good service is the very first point in the letter; they
inspected the item and it did not pass their standards of quality. When
ordering from an online retailer, this step is imperative yet so many miss it.
Zappos.com understands that the quality of the product is important and that
there is a chance that you will return it anyway if it is defective so they
might as well take an extra moment for this inspection to save everyone the
hassle later.</p>

<p>Following the inspection, they took the initiative to try and find the item
from a nearby supplier. Since they were not able to and instead of leaving me
in limbo indefinitely, they canceled my order to alive me of the burden of
having to do so myself and going somewhere else.</p>

<p>Honestly, getting this far in the letter, I&#8217;m already a very happy customer
(yes, even though I don&#8217;t have my product). To top things off even further,
Zappos.com assured me that this was not a normal occurrence for them and as a
nice gesture, they provided a $10 coupon to incentivize me to come back and to
help alleviate any inconvenience this may have caused. I can&#8217;t say enough how
important this one little letter is. <em>This</em> is customer service.</p>

<h2>It&#8217;s not all good</h2>

<p>The four previous examples are just a tiny fraction of stories out there about
quality customer service. There is also the flip side of the coin, those
companies who have <em>poor</em> customer service. I&#8217;m sure we could all name quite a
few companies that we consistently have bad service from and eventually you
learn just to avoid them where you can. I would only like to discuss a recent
scenario I had with the single-cup coffee manufacturer, Tassimo.</p>

<p>Up until this past winter, when I switched to Nespresso for a far superior
homemade espresso, I was a heavy consumer of Tassimo coffee and also a large
proponent of their brand. It did what it claimed and did it decently—well
enough for me to maintain a Tassimo Direct (a monthly subscription of coffee
automatically shipped to your home) membership with them for three years. Last
year, when I was evaluating alternatives to Tassimo, I put my Direct
membership on a shipment hold for 6 months. Unfortunately, that 6 months was
up recently. How did I know that? I was greeted by a lovely email yesterday
saying I had a shipment of coffee on its way. I looked at the UPS tracking
number and the shipment had actually gone out two days prior. Immediately
irked that I did not receive any kind of email as a heads up that the shipment
was going to occur, I picked up the phone to call their customer service.</p>

<p>Once connected to a human service representative, I explained the scenario.
I&#8217;m not sure where this person was from but she was very monotone, dry, and
pseudo-sympathetic to my issue. She &#8220;apologized&#8221; (as that&#8217;s probably what her
script told her to say), and explained that I could put my shipment on hold
for another 6 months. I replied with a stern &#8220;no&#8221; and said that I wanted to
cancel the subscription entirely and that it was poor service of them to send
out a shipment after a 6 month hold without so much as a courtesy email to the
customer giving them a heads up and providing a means of canceling. She
apologized again and replied with saying that the maximum hold for shipments
is 6 months and offered to put my shipments on hold for another 6 months.</p>

<p>Obviously, she missed the point entirely because she wasn&#8217;t listening, or
wasn&#8217;t comprehending the essence of the situation. I don&#8217;t blame her, English
is likely not her native language and she&#8217;s just doing this job because it&#8217;s
an income. I of course blame Tassimo. While they had lost a customer who was
at one time loyal, they also lost someone who used to rave about their product
and what a great alternative it was to other brands such as Keurig. If they
continue to burn bridges, especially in terms of customer service, they will
not be around much longer. As it is, it already seems they are not doing well
with the rising popularity of Keurig and Nespresso systems.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I honestly don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m being unreasonable here to demand quality customer
service from those whom I pay to provide me with a service or product. In my
opinion, its a company&#8217;s responsibility to understand <em>and</em> sympathize with
the needs of their customers. I&#8217;m not asking for monetary compensation every
time they mess up, or provide a faulty product; all I ask from them is that
they manage the situation in a courteous, efficient, and delightful manner
(see the Zappos.com letter—even if you take out the $10 coupon, it is still is
a great example of what I&#8217;m asking for).</p>

<p>Oftentimes, I&#8217;ve had people say to me how passionate I am about things I own,
especially in regards to recent purchases. I am passionate and proud most of
the time about the purchases I make. I strongly feel that I choose products
that are high-quality or provide excellent utility or entertainment to me.
When I find something that fits the bill, I will verbally share and sell that
item to friends and family (on a recent occassion, I sold three Nespresso
machines because people could see it was a quality product).</p>

<p>At the end of the day, I&#8217;ve not said anything that hasn&#8217;t been said before but
it doesn&#8217;t hurt to bring it up again. In most cases, you do what you can to
keep the customer happy. Do that, and you&#8217;ll win customers who will desire to
work with you because they know you understand and appreciate them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improve...don't prove]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/03/16/improve-dont-prove/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-16T01:14:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/03/16/improve-dont-prove</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whilst on the subway from work to Union Station in LA, I read an interesting
and inspiring article in this month&#8217;s issue of <em>Outdoor Photographer</em>. It was
an article titled <em>Don&#8217;t Prove&#8230;Improve!,</em> authored by nature photographer
Dewitt Jones. Jones narrated the story of his first published photo which was
in <em>National Geographic</em> and the experience he had in gaining a position there
as a photographer. The aspect he was highlighting the most was the discussion
he had with Bob Gilka, head of photography at <em>National Geographic. </em>Gilka
provided a bit of sound advice that can certainly be applied to the
programming field. Gilka told Jones that he was going to be working with the
best photographers in the world and that Jones didn&#8217;t need to prove himself to
Gilka or any of the other photographers he worked with. But the one thing he
did ask from Jones was to <em>improve</em> himself—always aspire to be a better
photographer.</p>

<p>This statement alone was enough to get me thinking about how relevant this was
to me as a programmer, especially on a team of other programmers. I think it&#8217;s
human nature for people to feel like they need to prove themselves to others
and in some cases that&#8217;s true, but for day-to-day tasks and projects that you
are collaborating with a team of people just like you, it&#8217;s pertinent to
remember the advice Gilka so sincerely offered.</p>

<p>Gilka went on to say that his photographers are expected to share and learn
from the other photographers. In other words, if you know of a technique,
share with your team; if you&#8217;re in need of critique, be humbled and let others
share with you. As programmers, there is no reason why we shouldn&#8217;t follow
this same mantra; we should be lifting each other up and providing
encouragement.</p>

<p>I work on a team where we get to work on some pretty great projects and so
much of the time our pride can get in the way of great development,
collaboration, and growth. This can cause issues from a few angles such as
being protective of one&#8217;s code rather than looking at it as the team&#8217;s code
and receiving feedback as a team to make it better. All in all it prevents the
team from moving forward and progressing in terms of skills, technology,
innovation, and team cohesion.</p>

<p>Jones describes his interaction with one of the photographers he met as well
as others he got to know with the following quote, &#8220;Technical help, honest
criticism and enthusiastic encouragement came from many, and my learning curve
went up with the trajectory of a space shuttle launch.&#8221; How many of you can
say the same thing about where you work? If you can, that&#8217;s fantastic! I would
guess that it&#8217;s not the case for many.</p>

<p>He goes on to make another good point that over the years he has seen so many
photographers waste time proving themselves to others that they missed the
opportunities to spend those same hours &#8220;improving their technique and
sharpening their eye&#8221;. How much better could we improve our development skills
with this at the forefront of our minds?</p>

<p>What&#8217;s the solution? How can you bring this into your team? For starters, you
can encourage your team to be more open. Speak to them about the benefits of
having an openness such as is described above. They likely won&#8217;t come around
instantly, but over time, the more you encourage this type of behavior, the
more it will become natural and easy. It&#8217;s also good to encourage community
code reviews where everyone and anyone can see and review code in a non-
demeaning manner. Again, it&#8217;s for everyone&#8217;s own good—to help them grow—to
help the team grow.</p>

<p>What are your thoughts? Can you relate to this?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Should JavaScript be like Java?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/03/08/when-should-javascript-be-like-java/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-08T20:25:51-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/03/08/when-should-javascript-be-like-java</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m architecting a JavaScript architecture for a project I&#8217;m working on. A lot
of the design patterns and methodologies I&#8217;m applying are from my experience
with Java and other server-side, traditional strictly typed languages.
JavaScript is different from Java which is both a good and bad thing. It&#8217;s
dynamic nature allows it to be light and extremely flexible—which comes at a
cost making it easy to become highly tangled, unmanageable, and unstructured.</p>

<p>Where do you draw the line? What are examples where you&#8217;ve done something
different in a JavaScript application than you would have done in a Java (or
similar) application?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make a shell script wait for you]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/03/08/make-a-shell-script-wait-for-you/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-08T14:34:54-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/03/08/make-a-shell-script-wait-for-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever want a loop to wait for you? <strong>read</strong> will read a line for you to use, or
in this case just ignore.</p>

<pre><code>for mod  in module-*.git ;
    do echo $mod ;
    cd $mod;
    git diff */ivy.xml;
    cd ..; echo "";
**    read foo;**
    echo "";
done
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blame it on the alcohol...really?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/02/24/blame-it-on-the-alcohol-really/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-24T04:03:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/02/24/blame-it-on-the-alcohol-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Glee&#8217;s &#8220;Blame it on the Alcohol&#8221; episode this week was a considerable
disappointment. I speak, of course, to the influential alcohol consumption by
the students of the high school. To be clear I don&#8217;t have a problem with
enjoying alcoholic drinks when one is 1) at a legal drinking age and 2)
responsible about it. This episode showcased that it&#8217;s ok to drink as long as
you are safe regardless of the legality and it also said there&#8217;s a chance you
could get a way with it and if you do, that makes it ok.</p>

<p>I will be the first to say that I by no means expect Glee to preach a morale
message on anything morale. However, alcohol is not something to joke about or
even shed light on in a silly manner. The point is that underaged teens are
not allowed to drink for reason—they are not responsible enough to consume a
body altering agent at whim. The consequences for the students on Glee were
only but a bit of humiliation on stage with a bunch of vomiting in front of
their peers&#8230;big deal.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s sad to me that shows that are as influential as Glee is harness their
power in ways that are going to turn heads to the creators of the show for
their own fame, glory, and preaching their personal agenda to the masses. Glee
could do so much for its audience that would be good for everybody. It doesn&#8217;t
need to have sex and alcohol to make a statement. I&#8217;ve been disappointed with
a couple of other previous episodes of Glee but won&#8217;t comment on those, but
this one really irked me due to the dangerous nature of alcohol in
irresponsible hands.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY Desktop Stand for Notebooks]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/01/22/diy-desktop-stand-for-notebooks/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-22T02:22:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2011/01/22/diy-desktop-stand-for-notebooks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After converting a white MacBook to our home media center, I decided the
footprint was too large to lay flat with the clamshell closed on our TV stand.
I came across the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002LARBWM?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=cf0d-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B002LARBWM">Twelve South BookArc</a> <img class="left" src="http://www.twelvesouth.com/static/assets/products/product/main_left_image/productImage_bapro.jpg"> and thought it would be the
perfect solution to stand the MacBook on end to take up less space. However,
at $50, I felt the price was a bit steep.</p>

<p><a href="http://kylehayes.info/files/2011/01/IMG_7929.jpg"><img src="http://kylehayes.net.kylehayes.info/files/2011/01/IMG_7929-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>Thinking how I could do something similar with items I already had
around the house, I thought of using a pair of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001E6CT8A?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=cf0d-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B001E6CT8A" title="Metal Economy Bookends">metal economy bookends</a>
that I seem to have a plethora of in my home office. Note that I&#8217;m using a
particular style of bookend that has a whole in the middle with the base bent
down and out.</p>

<p><a href="http://kylehayes.info/files/2011/01/IMG_7938.jpg"><img src="http://kylehayes.net.kylehayes.info/files/2011/01/IMG_7938-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>Place one bookend on top of the other&#8217;s base and slide them close
together, leaving enough room to stand the MacBook up vertically between the
two ends. Take the MacBook (or any notebook) and place it vertically between
the two stands and slide them together to hold the notebook in place.</p>

<p><a href="http://kylehayes.info/files/2011/01/IMG_7946.jpg"><img src="http://kylehayes.net.kylehayes.info/files/2011/01/IMG_7946-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>I used bookends that are about five inches in height which seem to
hold the MacBook fairly efficiently. You could also get some black felt and
glue it on the side of the bookends that touch the computer for better
friction.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grep Git Log]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/11/17/grep-git-log/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-17T17:08:15-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/11/17/grep-git-log</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve recently switched one of our big projects at work over to Git from
Perforce recently. Overall, its been good but has had quite the learning curve
for all of us to shift to this new paradigm. One of the things we&#8217;ve struggled
with a lot is just being able to easily see what&#8217;s changed in our commits,
comparing branch to branch etc. I&#8217;m always looking for ways to slice through
the information that git will report back.</p>

<p>I came across an interesting feature of git log yesterday. It allows you to
pass a simple grep string to the git log command and only the commits that
contain that string in their changeset description will be returned. This is
handy for us since we label all of our descriptions with our Version One story
or task ID.</p>

<p>The command is straightforward in its usage:</p>

<p>git log —grep=<grep_string></p>

<p>This turns what could be an unwieldy output of git log commits to a simple
eloquent output of a single (or shorter list) of commits:</p>

<p>$ git log &#8211;grep=B-03725</p>

<p>commit 938ec97072e6689a1065fe4aaf4ae6ae75352491</p>

<p>Author: Kyle Hayes &lt; my_email ></p>

<p>Date:   Mon Nov 15 08:42:15 2010 -0800</p>

<pre><code>FE integration refs: B-03725
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giving Posterous a try]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/08/17/giving-posterous-a-try/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-17T16:49:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/08/17/giving-posterous-a-try</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it is cliché to write a post about trying a new service that posts but
I gotta do it to give it a swing! I used to be a very frequent blogger over at
kylehayes.info in my ColdFusion days, but haven&#8217;t touched it much lately
because of how busy I&#8217;ve been. I figured if I can just send an email to write
a post about something, I just might be more apt to blog more frequently.
Although, that could mean that the quality of my content goes down, who knows,
we&#8217;ll see!</p>

<p>Cheers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Free JavaScript Tips Newsletter]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/06/16/new-free-javascript-tips-newsletter/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-16T14:44:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/06/16/new-free-javascript-tips-newsletter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s no surprise that I&#8217;m a huge advocate and fan of the <a href="http://www.dojotoolkit.org" title="DojoToolkit.org">Dojo toolkit</a>
when it comes to quality JavaScript development. It consistently delivers
quality results in my websites and web applications while also helping to keep
my code very maintainable and reusable. However, it&#8217;s also no surprise that
Dojo is not the most popular JavaScript toolkit. This is due to many factors,
one of which is the lack of strong marketing. It&#8217;s my desire to help and
support the Dojo team where I can especially in this area since it lacks so
much by offering a free newsletter to subscribers over at <a href="http://startdojo.com/?cmp=khnlpromo" title="Sign up for the free newsletter at StartDojo.com">StartDojo.com</a>.
Simply visit the site and register for free on the right-hand side.</p>

<p>The first issue has not been sent out yet as I wait for my subscribers, but I
promise to only provide useful, pragmatic JavaScript and Dojo programming
techniques as well as up-to-date industry news.</p>

<p><a href="http://startdojo.com/?cmp=khnlpromo" title="Sign up for the free newsletter at StartDojo.com">Sign up for free now!</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things about JavaScript I wish I knew earlier]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/04/20/things-about-javascript-i-wish-i-knew-earlier/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-20T19:37:44-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/04/20/things-about-javascript-i-wish-i-knew-earlier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Christian Hellman wrote another excellent JavaScript article over at <a href="http://www.smashingmagazine.com/">Smashing
Magazine</a>. This time he addresses styles and techniques of coding that is
widely supported, accepted, and expected by good JavaScript developers. If
you’ve been programming JavaScript for awhile, you’ll notice much of the stuff
is different now than it was less than a decade ago now that JavaScript has
evolved and improved based on the  needs of the JavaScript community as well
as the capabilities of modern-day browsers.</p>

<p>Personally, the ones I’ve fallen victim to most recently are shortcut
notations. Having a Java background, I always wanted to create new Objects and
Arrays using the “new” keyword and constructing. During the writing of
<a href="http://startdojo.com/buy">Getting Started with Dojo</a>, Peter Higgins (the technical reviewer) pounded
in my head that today, objects are created like var foo = {} and arrays are
created like var bar = []. Christian discusses this in the article (and a bit
more in detail).</p>

<p>Using JSON as a data format is another one I can strongly relate to,
especially with his mention of using arrays and delimited strings in the past.
Today, there will not be a project that goes by where I need data brought in
and I will always choose JSON if it’s available due to its native support in
modern day JavaScript.</p>

<p>I personally am always looking for ways to make my JavaScript run faster. As
developers, we so often get caught up in the moment of getting something to
work and simply implement a solution in a way that just came natural and was
easy, we don’t go back to see if we can make it more efficient—especially in
terms of browser memory usage. There have been many times I’ve seen a simple
for loop accessing data in a way that is calling another method to fetch the
data, instead of caching the data once and accessing the local cache.
Christian brought up another way to make your page more efficient in terms of
events that I had not thought of. His example perfectly illustrates a
situation in which you want to listen for the click event on a set of list
items inside an unordered list. Instead of looping through each list item and
adding an event handler, you can simply add an event handler to the parent of
this list (the ul). From here you can determine which li was clicked. This
assuming that you understand that events in the DOM roll up from the bottom
when an event occurs. This means that if you click an li,if that click is not
handled on the li, it will roll up to the ul and so forth.</p>

<p>Finally the last few points on anonymous functions with the module pattern,
configuration, interacting with the back end, and browser specific code, I
cannot stress enough to read and understand these the best you can. These four
points that he clearly makes are utterly important in ensuring you are an
efficient JavaScript developer. This will set you apart from being a good
JavaScript dev, to an excellent JavaScript dev—proving you know how the
language works and how to best control it and use it as it should be used.</p>

<p>I highly respect Christian’s articles and his advice and I recommend you head
his comments where you see fit. You can read the full article on Smashing
Magazine below:</p>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/amJ8sj">http://bit.ly/amJ8sj</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 Forms]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/04/13/html5-forms/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-13T15:06:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/04/13/html5-forms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With all the buzz of HTML5, most of it has been centered around the new video
and canvas tags, however, so much more is being added and spec’ed out. One
particular area that has been given some much needed love is forms.</p>

<p>Some new form input types that we get are:</p>

<ul>
<li>search</li>
<li>tel</li>
<li>url</li>
<li>email</li>
<li>datetime, date, month, week, time, and datetime-local</li>
<li>number</li>
<li>range</li>
<li>color</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with that, some validation. But what browsers are supporting this new
functionality? Check out the litmus tests here: <a href="http://cl.ly/4Bq">http://cl.ly/4Bq</a></p>

<p><strong>Update: </strong>See if your browser passes the HTML5 &#8220;Acid&#8221; test: <a href="http://html5test.com/">http://html5test.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debate on Automated Acceptance Testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/04/09/debate-on-automated-acceptance-testing/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-09T14:02:33-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/04/09/debate-on-automated-acceptance-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Part of agile software development is the practice of acceptance testing to
ensure the appropriate business requirements, use cases, and ensure confidence
in the delivered product. This process is commonly recommended to be automated
so the tests can be easily run at a given time as well as be consistent. James
Shore created and encouraged the agile community to use his automated testing
framework (Fit) to create these tests.</p>

<p>The problem is that it was meant for the business to be creating these tests,
not the developers, however, it turns out that the developers were tasked with
creating them instead which is a “maintenance burden”.</p>

<p>Shore now believes that automating the acceptance testing is <em>not</em> a good
idea, summarized by the following two points:</p>

<p>1.       The real planned benefit of an automated acceptance tool, like Fit,
was that the business folks (&#8220;customers&#8221;) would write executable examples
themselves. History has shown that very rarely occurs. In a few cases testers
do, but in the majority of cases these tests are written by the developers.</p>

<p>2.       These tests often become a real maintenance burden, as they are slow
and brittle, and often hard to refactor. On this point, that end-to-end
&#8220;integration tests&#8221; present a higher cost than they are worth, JB Rainsberger
has a <a href="http://jbrains.ca/category/named/integrated-tests-are-a-scam">great series of articles</a> explaining his rational why.</p>

<p>What do you think?</p>

<p>Full article on InfoQ: <a href="http://bit.ly/a2002q">http://bit.ly/a2002q</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easily Generate Placeholder Images in Designs and Web Pages]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/01/27/easily-generate-placeholder-images-in-designs-and-web-pages/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-27T15:26:10-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2010/01/27/easily-generate-placeholder-images-in-designs-and-web-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across a neat site called dummyimage.com that allows you to append an
image size to it&#8217;s URL as so: <a href="http://dummyimage.com/300x250">http://dummyimage.com/300x250</a>. However,
what I didn&#8217;t like about it, is that I could not add text to the image to
describe what the image is a placeholder for. I took upon myself to create my
own service that does this and I plan on expanding it to do more as well.</p>

<p>Last night I created <a href="http://fpoimg.com">fpoimg.com</a>. It works in very much the same way as
dummyimage.com, only you can add text to your images. The next iteration of
the site will allow you to change the colors of the background and foreground.
Anyway, the way you use the site is if you want to create a basic placeholder
or FPO (For Placement Only) image you simply go to
<a href="http://fpoimg.com/345x480">http://fpoimg.com/345x480</a> and the image will be provided to you. You can
save this image if you like, or you can refer to it directly in your code such
as in an image tag: <code>&lt;img src="http://fpoimg.com/345x480"&gt;</code></p>

<p>The first number is your width in pixels, the second is your height in pixels.
Additionally, if you want to add some text to the image to describe it as a
placeholder, you simply append that to the URL as so:
<a href="http://fpoimg.com/200x200/Advertisement">http://fpoimg.com/345x480/Advertisement</a></p>

<p>This will create the following image:</p>

<p><img src="http://fpoimg.com/345x480/Advertisement" alt="" /></p>

<p>It&#8217;s really that basic! Here are some more examples: <img src="http://fpoimg.com/300x250/MREC" alt="" /> <img src="http://fpoimg.com/728x90/Banner" alt="" /></p>

<p>I of course do plan on tweaking this service as needed such as caching the
images and providing the ability to change their colors. If the service
becomes more popular, I have a feeling I&#8217;ll need to invoke some kind of limit
as well so as not to crash the server.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting StartED with Dojo now available!]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2009/12/30/getting-started-with-dojo-now-available/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-30T15:38:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2009/12/30/getting-started-with-dojo-now-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The book that I&#8217;ve been writing for the past nine months is finally published
and available for purchase. Below are the details as posted on the companion
site, <a href="http://startdojo.com" title="Go to startdojo.com">startdojo.com</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Getting StartED with Dojo is finally available for <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430225211?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=startdojo-com-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1430225211">purchase</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=startdojo-com-200&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1430225211" alt="" />!
About nine months ago I was approached by Apress to author a book on the <a href="http://">Dojo
toolkit</a>. After a long journey of authoring my first book, the final phase
is complete as the book is now officially published and out in the wild. While
the actual publish date was December 28th, I&#8217;m sure it will be a little while
before you start seeing it on the shelves of popular brick and mortar
bookstore shelves such as Borders and Barnes &amp; Noble. For now, you can
certainly <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430225211?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=startdojo-com-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1430225211">order it on Amazon</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=startdojo-com-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1430225211" alt="" />.</p></blockquote>

<p>Getting StartED with Dojo has fan page on Facebook: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Getting-StartED-with-Dojo/224855113411" title="Getting StartED with Dojo">Getting StartED with
Dojo</a> | <a href="http://www.facebook.com/business/dashboard/" title="Make your own badge!">Promote Your Page Too</a> <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Getting-StartED-with-Dojo/224855113411" title="Getting StartED with Dojo"><img src="http://badge.facebook.com/badge/224855113411.2790.2105382221.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>You may also <a href="http://twitter.com/startdojo" title="Follow @startdojo on Twitter!">follow @startdojo on Twitter</a> for up to date news and
information relating to the Dojo toolkit and community.</p>

<p>I will mostly be using this site for updates to the book such as corrections
to the code and copy. In addition, I will be posting tips and resources for
learning more about the Dojo toolkit. A lot of work went into the creation of
this book and I hope you enjoy it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon.com's Black Friday Deals Available Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2009/11/23/amazon-coms-black-friday-deals-available-now/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-23T14:45:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2009/11/23/amazon-coms-black-friday-deals-available-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every year Amazon.com has some <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FBlack-Friday-After-Thanksgiving-Sale%2Fb%3Fie%3DUTF8%26node%3D384082011%26ref_%3Dpe%255F67050%255F13524000%255Fpe%255Fbtn&amp;tag=cf0d-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957" title="Amazon.com's Black Friday Deals">incredible deals</a> on some of their
merchandise. This year, they&#8217;ve started even earlier to get you in the holiday
shopping spirit by starting to offer their <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FBlack-Friday-After-Thanksgiving-Sale%2Fb%3Fie%3DUTF8%26node%3D384082011%26ref_%3Dpe%255F67050%255F13524000%255Fpe%255Fbtn&amp;tag=cf0d-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957" title="Amazon.com's Black Friday Deals">deals TODAY</a>.</p>

<p>They&#8217;ve said that all of their deals are limited in quantity but will line up
new items after they sell out throughout the day.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FBlack-Friday-After-Thanksgiving-Sale%2Fb%3Fie%3DUTF8%26node%3D384082011%26ref_%3Dpe%255F67050%255F13524000%255Fpe%255Fbtn&amp;tag=cf0d-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957" title="Amazon.com's Black Friday Deals">Visit Amazon.com&#8217;s Black Friday Deals</a></p>

<p><a href="http://ws.amazon.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ID=V20070822%2FUS%2Fcf0d-20%2F8001%2F8c30b9d4-988a-4a90-8d1b-88eee45f908e&amp;Operation=NoScript">Amazon.com Widgets</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Your Kid the Next Face of Gap?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylehayes.github.com/2009/10/01/is-your-kid-the-next-face-of-gap/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-01T02:22:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylehayes.github.com/2009/10/01/is-your-kid-the-next-face-of-gap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a long time since I&#8217;ve posted, I know it, but I have good excuses!
The first is still an excuse as I&#8217;m still working on it, but, I was asked by
<a href="http://www.apress.com">Apress</a> / <a href="http://www.friendsofed.com">Friends of ED</a> to write a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430225211?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=cf0d-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1430225211">book</a> on the <a href="http://www.dojotoolkit.org">Dojo JavaScript
Toolkit</a>. It&#8217;s been quite the journey to say the least. It has been a
desire of mine in the past few years to publish a technical book. When Apress
approached me, I couldn&#8217;t resist. It&#8217;s been a lot of work but it&#8217;s almost
done. You can check it out and pre-order it on Amazon.com! Needless to say
I&#8217;ve had my head in Dojo quite a bit the past few months.</p>

<p>With that, I&#8217;ve also been working on a very large project at work that I&#8217;m one
of the technical leads on. That project is the <a href="http://family.go.com/gapcastingcall/">Gap Casting Call</a> which is
a contest that Gap runs every year to find the next faces of BabyGap and
GapKids. They partnered with us at Family.com to build and host the online
photo contest. Enter your kids to get a chance at winning! There are a lot of
great <a href="http://family.go.com/gapcastingcall/prizes/">prizes</a> and a lot of great <a href="http://family.go.com/gapcastingcall/galleries/">entries</a>!</p>

<p>On to my next project at work where I get to learn and use GWT. More to come
in the future I&#8217;m sure. Until then, thanks for staying up to date with me, and
sorry it has been so long since I&#8217;ve posted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
